karen kuzmiak



designer | developer | creative

who i am

I am a UI designer who crosses over to UX and product arena as well. My talents include deciphering puzzles, organizing tons of information, and seeing the big picture while noticing the small details. My 50/50 brain loves to integrate technology with art in order to create a user experiences that transcends the 'usual.'

I would love to learn to play the piano.

education

SAN DIEGO STATE UNIVERSITY | 2005

Bachelor's of Arts, Linguistics Minors: Italian & French Magna Cum Laude

certifications

INTERACTIVE MEDIA | 2020

FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPMENT | 2020

San Diego Community College District

publications

SPEAK IN A WEEK - ITALIAN | 2005

Penton Publishina

skills

- Design systems
- Visual design
- Motion graphics
- Lavout
- Typography
- Front-end engineering

tools | expertise

- Fiama
- Adobe Creative Suite
- Affinity
- Wireframina
- Prototyping
- HTML / CSS / Javascript
- Version control

contact



KARENKUZMIAK-PORTFOLIO.NETLIFY.APP



KAREN@THEKUZICOLLABORATIVE.COM

experience

227 InfoSec, Inc. | www.phish-test.com

PRODUCT DESIGNER / FRONT-END DEVELOPER, freelance | CURRENT

- Leading design and influencing product strategy for 227's GoPhish Phishing Quiz.
- Audit needs of users and define product plan for best user experience.

San Diego 350 | www,semprafracksourfuture.org

UI DESIGNER / FRONT-END DEVELOPER, freelance | 2021 - 2022

- Responsible for developing ideas and concepts for responsive web design.
- Identified and built in efficiencies into design process.

ETI Employee Training Institute | www.trainwitheti.com

UI / UX DESIGNER / FRONT-END DEVELOPER, contract/freelance | 2019 - 2022

- Led project design efforts responsible for leading and inspiring project team.
- Work closely with teammates to produce design solutions using sketches, wireframes, and high-fidelity mock-ups.
- HTML / CSS / Javascript coding and designing for multiple platform screens.
- Extensive user research, personas, and journey mapping.

BeatBabel

QUALITY ASSURANCE (QA) LOCALIZATION SPECIALIST, contract | 2018 - 2019

- Verify linguistic accuracy and check for typographical, grammatical and punctuation errors in several languages.
- Translate documents from Italian to English to Italian.
- Ensure that quality standards, accuracy and consistency is maintained throughout files.

Chickrigger | www.chickrigger.wordpress.com

FOUNDER / CREATOR | 2018 - 2019

Weekly blog used for communicating with crew at the same time keeping the interested public abreast of the rigging progress of the iconic HMS Surprise, a replica 18th century frigate.

- Created graphic artwork to improve and drive audience engagement.
- Leveraged advanced organizational development, business, and planning skills to conceptualize, build, and maintain this online resource for the historical ship industry.

Maritime Museum of San Diego

PROJECT MANAGER / DIRECTOR OF FACILITIES | 2014 - 2019

Managed crew to rig and maintain two iconic ships: 18th century HMS Surprise and 16th century San Salvador.

- Mentored crew members in the rigging techniques and sailing of the period.
- Support and lead the development of long-term vision and quarterly goals.
- Developed inventory system and organizational structure of all rigging parts.

Pos Pizza Lounge & Bar

GRAPHIC DESIGNER, freelance | 2011-2015

- Implemented brand strategy including creation of logo design with custom typography.
- Designed digital content for advertising and brand campaigns varying across multiple mediums.